# Martha Sharpe

## Web Developer

(701) 430-7151

marthasharpe2020@gmail.com marthasharpe.netlify.app github.com/marthasharpe linkedin.com/in/marthasharpe2020

## Summary

I am a self-taught developer specializing in JavaScript, React and Redux. I have learned through building and deploying apps, pushing to GitHub and getting peer code reviews on LinkedIn. Because of my contagious enthusiasm and passion for learning, I was chosen as a LinkedIn Top Voice for Web Development last year. I love the daily challenges of web development: writing quality code, learning new technologies, and solving complex problems. I have been continuing to learn through freelance opportunities. A Squarespace site using Mailchimp, and a React-Native app for sharing videos. I look forward to working on a team that is passionate about their product..

#### **Tech Stack**

JavaScript | React | Redux | React Native | Node | Express | MongoDB | Bootstrap | Git

## **Work History**

#### React-Native Developer, Freelance - Remote

2020-present

- Building a cross-platform mobile app using React-Native and the Expo-cli.
- Responsible for designing and building the front end of the application.
- Implementing user login, access to camera, and social media sharing options.
- Communicating with the client to determine requirements and meet expectations.

## Web Developer, Business of Healthcare - Remote

2020-present

- Built a media website using Squarespace. <a href="https://www.bohseries.com/">https://www.bohseries.com/</a>
- Discussed design options with the business owner to meet requirements.
- Integrated third-party services such as Eventbrite and Mailchimp.
- Set up embedded live stream and live chat capabilities.

#### Homeschooling Parent, Self-employed - Atlanta, GA

2010-present

- Managed the accounts and logistics of a home-business
- Raised and homeschooled four children using Agile methodology
- Mastered time-management, prioritizing, and working under pressure

## Head Youth Minister, Thomas Aquinas Newman Center - Grand Forks, ND 2009-2010

- Coordinated social and educational events for college students
- Delegated administrative duties to three other ministers
- Approached and engaged new students to make them feel welcome

## Head Bartender, United Airlines Red Carpet Club - Arlington, VA

2008-2009

- Learned to mix 250+ drinks and track several orders at once
- Provided excellent customer service to business-class clientele
- Trained in Techniques of Alcohol Management

#### Karate Instructor, American Black Belt Academy - Colorado Springs, CO

2002-2005

- Earned my black belt and karate instructor certification
- Taught self-defense classes to children and adults at the main school
- Started a karate club in college as an official student organization

#### **Projects**

#### MySchool: Full-Stack Website - https://my-school.netlify.com/

A website for saving online learning resources. Built a REST API using Node, Express, and MongoDB with Mongoose schemas. Implemented user login with password encryption and JWT authentication. Client-side is a basic CRUD application built with React. Used Redux for state management and redux-thunk for asynchronous API calls. Also used React-Router-DOM for dynamic routing and React-Bootstrap for styling. github.com/marthasharpe/myschool-back - github.com/marthasharpe/MySchool-front

#### Hangémon: React-Redux Game

An original game for kids and adults to guess the names of random Pokemon.

A React App using Redux for state management and Redux-thunk for the API call.

Mobile-first design using React-Bootstrap. Learned to control all aspects of the UI using state.

Hangemon.netlify.com - github.com/marthasharpe/hang-pokemon

## Mix Master: JavaScript Game

A game to learn to mix cocktails. Original concept and design from my bartending days. I wrote this from scratch using ES6 JavaScript and styled it with CSS grid and flexbox. Used an object-oriented approach by creating a Drink class constructor.

Bartending-game.netlify.com - github.com/marthasharpe/Bartending-Game

#### Education

## University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

2003-2007

- BA in Classical Studies, Honors Scholar
- Background in Calculus and physical sciences
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude